Guide to the Pennsylvania Environmental Council Collection, 1970-1998 AIS.1999.18
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Pennsylvania Environmental Council Collection
1970-1999
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Pennsylvania Environmental Council
AIS.1999.18
78.75 Linear Feet (33 boxes)
Founded in 1969, the Pennsylvania Environmental Council (PEC) become a group dedicated to legislative action regarding the environment and amassed a large amount of material pertaining to environmental issues. The collection contains information acquired by the PEC throughout the 1970s-1990s on issues relevant to their policies and actions (i.e., acid rain, air pollution, energy, hazardous materials, land, pesticides, transportation, water, and the wetlands). The information collected by PEC takes the form of news clippings, articles, correspondence, publications and pamphlets. PEC also published their own newsletters relevant to ongoing legislation regarding environmental issues. The PEC remains an active organization today.
History
The environmental movement in the United States took hold during the 1960s at a time when college campuses across the country were taking part in Earth Day celebrations. There was a renewed focus on the issues and the current state of the environment. In 1969, a small number of conservationists joined together to take action on behalf of the environment in Pennsylvania. This group saw the need for a statewide citizen's organization that had the capability to link activities of prior organizations including watershed associations, Audubon societies, garden clubs and conservancies, Trout Unlimited, the Sierra Club, the Federation of Sportsmen's Clubs, and the League of Women Voters. This organization was named the Pennsylvania Environmental Coordinating Council and was later changed to the Pennsylvania Environmental Council (PEC).
In October 1969, it was decided that the Pennsylvania Environmental Council was to become the group dedicated to legislative action. The PEC incorporated into their mission a lobbying group for environmental protection legislation and regulations. Their counterpart, the Environmental Planning and Information Center (EPIC), was to serve as more of a tax exempt research/information group. At the time of this split, both groups were incorporated into the Pennsylvania system in January 1970.
Although PEC and EPIC existed as separate entities, they worked closely together on various issues. The physical separation only existed for the purpose of cooperating with federal tax laws. PEC and EPIC worked out of the same office and slowly grew as an organization.
PEC used lobbying techniques to pass environmental legislation through the Pennsylvania government. In addition, the PEC also published their own newsletters such as, News and Views, which alerted citizens of upcoming environmental meetings and current legislative issues of environmental concern. PEC and EPIC also presented conferences on environmental policies and issues to relay information to the people on the current state of affairs. The information portrayed at the conferences included the environmental issues dealing with air, water, solid waste, land protection, education, population, growth, surface mining, and toxic waste.
PEC successfully expanded as an organization throughout the 1970s through the presentation of these conferences, newsletters, lobbying, and seminars. In 1973, EPIC was renamed the Pennsylvania Environmental Research Foundation. Then, in the mid-1980s, the Pennsylvania Environmental Research Foundation merged into the PEC and the two groups became known simply as the PEC. The merging of these two sections of Pennsylvania's environmental organizations created the version of the PEC as it functions today "joining policy work with on-the-ground education projects" (PEC).
Throughout the 1970s and into the beginning of the 1980s, PEC had a number of primary activities. PEC aimed to bring all environmental issues to the surface in Pennsylvania and address them each accordingly. Once an environmental issue was surfaced, PEC aimed for the passage of legislation and regulation for that issue. Legislation, such as the Flood Plain Control Act passed in October 1978, was passed successfully because of consistent lobbying on behalf of PEC.
PEC has not changed its approach to environmental issues. PEC has become an informational source on environmental issues and policy. Today, PEC provides various informative programs. In addition, the organization has grown from one original office to five and is now staffed by 33 members.
Scope and Content Notes
The Pennsylvania Environmental Council (PEC) collection details the environmental movement and its impact in Pennsylvania throughout the 1970s and 1990s. A large segment of the materials in the collection are information files that have been gathered by members of the PEC on issues pertinent to Pennsylvania areas. Some of these issues include acid rain, air pollution, energy, hazardous materials, land, pesticides, transportation, waste, water, and the wetlands. Within each of these issues, the PEC collected documentation to detail how some materials were detrimental to the stability of the Pennsylvania environment. In addition, the PEC often published their own newsletters, handbooks, pamphlets, and articles to educate the public on legislative issues.
Today the PEC is still an effective lobbying organization often involved with legislative affairs. In 1999 the Archives Service Center received the PEC's earliest records documenting their activities from 1970 through the 1990s. In its entirety, this collection is full of research in the background of environmental issues and the active role the PEC has played in Pennsylvania's environmental movement.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Previous Citation
Pennsylvania Environmental Council Collection, 1970-1998, AIS.1999.18, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into the following nine series:
Series I. Environmental Concerns
Series II. Workshops
Series III. Meetings/Conferences
Series IV. Legislation
Series V. Environmental Activities/Projects
Series VI. Department of Environmental Resources
Series VII. Handbooks/Policies
Series VIII. Publications
Series IX. Videotapes
Acquisition Information
Gift of Andrew McElvaine in August 1999.
Green movement -- Pennsylvania; Acid rain -- Pennsylvania; Air -- Pollution -- Pennsylvania; Water -- Pollution -- Pennsylvania; Hazardous wastes -- Pennsylvania; Wetlands -- Pennsylvania; Pesticides -- Environmental aspects -- Pennsylvania; Environmental protection -- Pennsylvania; Environmentalists -- Pennsylvania; Correspondence; Clippings (Information artifacts); Pamphlets; Newsletters; Associations; Environmentalism -- Pennsylvania; Environment; Nonprofit organizations -- Pennsylvania; Ecology -- Research; Environmental law -- Pennsylvania; Environmental policy -- Pennsylvania; Pennsylvania. Department of Environmental Protection; Pennsylvania. Department of Environmental Resources; Pennsylvania Environmental Council
- Environmental Concerns, 1971-1999; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  The Pennsylvania Environmental Council (PEC) has collected an ample amount of material regarding environmental issues concerning the Pennsylvania region. Included within the material are brochures, news clippings, informational booklets, correspondence, and journal articles. This series reflects PEC's research interests and gives evidence to their views on certain environmental conditions in Pennsylvania. This series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Acid Rain-General Information, 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Acid Rain-General Information, 1982-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Acid Rain-General Information, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Acid Rain-General Information, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Acid Rain-Bibliography, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Acid Rain-Canada, 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Acid Rain-Causes of Emissions, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Acid Rain-Control, 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Acid Rain-Co-firing, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Acid Rain-Effect on Aquatic Organisms, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Acid Rain-Effect on Forest/Agriculture, 1984-1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Acid Rain-Effects on Human Health, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Acid Rain-Effect on Water, 1980-1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Acid Rain-Types of Non-Rain, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Acid Rain-Workshops, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Air Pollution-General Information, 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Air Pollution-General Information, 1980-1991 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Air Pollution-General Information, 1983-1989 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Air Pollution-Cars and Emissions, 1982-1993 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Air Pollution-Clean Air Act, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Air Pollution-Coke Plants, 1987-1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Air Pollution-Global Warming, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Air Pollution-Global Warming, 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Air Pollution-Global Warming, 1989-1992 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Air Pollution-Health, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Air Pollution-Non-road Engine and Vehicle Emission, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Air Pollution-Philadelphia Data, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Air Pollution-Radon, 1986-1992 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Air Pollution-Radon, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Air Pollution-Radon News Clippings, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Air Pollution-Radon Services Directory, 1987-1993 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Air Pollution-Reports and Plans, 1982-1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Air Pollution-Reports and Plans, 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Air Pollution-Stratospheric Ozone, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Air Pollution-Urban Ozone, 1987-1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Air Pollution-UV Light (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Air Quality-Information, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Architecture-Sustainable, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Billboards, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Biodiversity, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Biodiversity, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Clothing, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Coastlines-New Jersey, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Delaware Valley Data, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Delaware Valley Data, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Eco-Tourism, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Endangered Species, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Electromagnetic Fields, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Electromagnetic Radiation, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Energy, 1985-1993 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Energy, 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Energy-Alternative Fuels, 1989-1993 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Energy-Appliances, 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Energy-Co-generation, 1986-1992 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Energy-Coal, Centralia, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Energy-Coal, 1985-1992 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Energy-Coal, 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Energy-Coal, Slurry Pipeline, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Energy-Coal, Surface Mining, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Energy-Coal, Deep Mining, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Energy-Coal, Surface Mining, 1979-1987 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Energy-Coal, Subsidence, 1979-1986 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Energy-Coal, Technology Project, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Energy-Coal, Conservation, 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Energy-Conservation, 1983-1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Energy-Conservation, Least Cost Alternative, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Energy-Culm Burning, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Energy-Education, 1982-1991 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Energy-Facility, 1978-1981 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Energy-Mine Reclamation, 1984-1988 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Energy-Publications, 1981-1991 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Energy-Mass Transportation, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Energy-Nuclear, 1987-1993 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Energy-Nuclear, 1982-1989 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Energy-Nuclear, Limmerick, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Energy-Oil, Offshore Drilling, Alaska Center for the Environment, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Energy-Oil, Offshore Drilling, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Energy-Oil and Gas Pollution, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Energy-Oil and Gas, 1990-1998 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Energy-Renewable, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Energy-Solar, 1988-1992 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Energy-Solar, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Energy-Synthetic Fuel, 1982-1985 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Environmental Education, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Environmental Education, 1985-1998 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Environmental Education, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Environmental/Occupational Health, 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Environmental Resources Inventory, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Environmental Shopping, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Farmland Preservation, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Flood Insurance, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Food, 1985-1993 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Food Irradiation, 1988-1992 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Graphic Arts-Environmentally Friendly, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Green Business, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Greenwire, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Hazardous Materials-Above Ground Storage Tanks, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Hazardous Materials-Chemicals, 1987-1994 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Hazardous Materials-Chemicals, Asbestos, 1979-1988 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Hazardous Materials-Chemicals, Asbestos, 1979-1994 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Hazardous Materials-Chemicals, Asbestos, 1983-1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Hazardous Materials-Chemicals, Benzene, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Hazardous Materials-Chemicals, Dioxin, 1983-1993 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Hazardous Materials-Chemicals, EPA Emergency Preparedness, 1988-1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Hazardous Materials-Chemicals, Heavy Metals, 1974-1992 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Hazardous Materials-Chemicals, Heavy Metals, 1973-1987 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Hazardous Materials-Chemicals, Right to Know, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Hazardous Materials-Chemicals, Right to Know, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Hazardous Materials-Chemicals, Fiberglass, 1976-1987 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Hazardous Materials-Chemicals, Flourocarbons, 1989-1992 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Hazardous Materials-Chemicals, Formaldehyde, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Hazardous Materials-Chemicals, General, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Hazardous Materials-Chemicals, Methylene Chloride, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Hazardous Materials-Chemicals, Naptha, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Hazardous Materials-Chemicals, National Toxic Program Status Report, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Hazardous Materials-Chemicals, PCBs, 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Hazardous Materials-Chemicals, PCBs, 1982-1987 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Hazardous Materials-Chemicals, Perchloroethylene, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Hazardous Materials-Transportation, 1986-1988 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Hazardous Materials-Underground Storage Tanks, 1988-1993 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Hazardous Materials-Underground Storage Tanks, 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Land-Agriculture, 1987-1993 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Land-Erosion and Sedimentation, 1981-1991 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Land-Forestry, 1990-1993 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Land-Forestry, pamphlets, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Land-Forestry, Parks, 1989-1991 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Land-Forestry, Parks, 1985-1992 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Land-Parks, Governor's Conference, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Land-Publications, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Land-Rain Forest, 1987-1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Land-Redevelopment, 10000 Friends, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Land-Redevelopment, Greenspace Alliance, 1996-1999 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Land-Redevelopment, Pamphlets, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Land-Soil Contamination, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Land-Tree Ordinances and Inventory, 1987-1991 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Magnetic Levitation, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - NAFTA, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - National Gypsy Moth, 1982-1994 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Non-Point Source Pollution, 1985-1992 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Non-Point Source Pollution, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Nutrient Management, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Ocean Pollution, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Pesticides-Alternatives, 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Pesticides-Alternatives, 1987-1990 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Pesticides-Articles, 1984-1989 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Pesticides, 1983-1993 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Pesticides-Disposal, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Pesticides-EPA Toxic Program 33/50, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Pesticide-Facts and Guides, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Pesticides-Health, 1988-1992 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Pesticides-Individual, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Pesticides-Lawn Care, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Pesticides-Legislation/Registration, 1971-1987 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Pesticides-Publications, 1986-1988 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Pesticides-Use in Forest, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Pesticides-Water Pollution, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Pollution-Prevention, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Population Data, 1990-1997 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Population Data, 1973, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Recreation, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Recreation, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Risk Assessment, 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Risk Assessment, 1985-1987 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Risk Assessment, 1983-1999 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Sustainable Development, 1992-1994 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Sustainable Development, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Transportation-Air Quality, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Transportation-Car Pooling, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Transportation-Car Use Reduction, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Transportation-Congestion, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Transportation-Cost Commuting, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Transportation-Decentralization, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Transportation-Environment, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Transportation-Gas Tax, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Transportation-General, 1989-1994 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Transportation-Idling, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Transportation-Land Use, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Transportation-Legislation, 1990-1993 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Transportation-Low Emission Vehicles, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Transportation-National Trends, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Transportation-SEPTA, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Transportation Tab, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Waste, 1982, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Waste-Hazardous, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Waste-Hazardous, 1981-1985 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Waste-Hazardous Household, 1980-1994 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Waste-Hazardous Household, 1982-1985 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Waste-Hazardous Household, 1985-1989 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Waste-Hazardous Household, 1985-1988 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Waste-Hazardous Household, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Waste-Hazardous Household, Aerosols, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Waste-Hazardous Household, Batteries, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Waste-Hazardous Household, Cleaners, 1988-1993 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Waste-Hazardous Household, Cosmetics, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Waste-Hazardous Household, Darkroom, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Waste-Hazardous Household, Paint, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Waste-Hazardous Household, PCB/CFC, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Waste-Hazardous Household, Pesticides, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Waste-Hazardous Household, Pets, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Waste-Hazardous Household, Solvents, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Waste-Hazardous Household, Wine/Beer, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, 1982-1987 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, 1982-1985 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Center for Hazardous Materials Research, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Deep Well Injection, 1985, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Directory Promotional Brochures, 1980-1984 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Incineration, 1986-1993 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Landfilling, 1983-1991 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Ocean Incineration, 1984-1986 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Pamphlets, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Pennsylvania, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Pennsylvania, 1985, 1986, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Pennsylvania, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Pennsylvania, 1985-1987 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Recycling, 1980-1992 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Recycling Oil, 1990-1992 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Recycling Oil, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Reduction, 1986-1988 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Reduction, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Reduction, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Siting, 1979-1989 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Siting, 1981, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Siting, 1981-1988 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Siting, 1980-1987 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Siting, 1979-1991 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Waste-Hazardous Management, Treatment, 1987, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Waste-Hazardous, Public Participation, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Waste-Hazardous, Public Participation, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Waste-Hazardous, Radioactive High-Level, 1987-1989 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Waste-Hazardous, Radioactive Low-Level, 1987-1993 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Waste-Hazardous, Radioactive Low-Level, 1988-1991 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Waste-Hazardous, Radioactive Low-Level, 1987-1989 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Waste-Hazardous, Radioactive Low-Level Management, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Waste-Hazardous, Radioactive Low Level Management, 1986-1994 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Waste-Hazardous, Radioactive Low Level Management Siting, 1986-1993 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Waste-Hazardous, Radioactive Low-Level Management Siting, 1985, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Waste-Hazardous, Small Quantity Generators, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Waste-Hazardous, Small Quantity Generators, 1984-1986 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Waste-Hazardous, Small Quantity Generators, 1986-1988 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Waste-Hazardous, Small Quantity Generators, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Waste-Hazardous, Superfund, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Waste-Hazardous, Superfund, 1985-1991 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Waste-Hazardous, Superfund, 1983-1985 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Waste-Hazardous, Superfund Sites in Pennsylvania, 1985-1990 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Waste-Hazardous, Superfund Sites in Pennsylvania, 1983-1986 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Waste-Hazardous, Superfund Sites in Pennsylvania, 1985-1989 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Waste-Hazardous, Superfund in the States, 1983-1986 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Waste-Hazardous, Superfund in the States, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Waste-Household Collection Programs, 1981-1993 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Waste-Household Collection Programs, 1986, 1987, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Waste-Infectious, 1988-1991 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Waste-Management, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Waste-Management, 1980, 1983, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Waste-Solid, 1989-1992 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Waste-Solid Management, 1988-1991 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Waste-Solid Management, 1985-1989 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Waste-Solid Management Composting, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Waste-Solid Management Co-Compositing, 1986-1992 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Waste-Solid Management Co-Disposal, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Waste-Solid Management Disposable Diapers, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 5)